# Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

jcyhsiao@umich.edu • +1 (734) 730-0963 • http://joeyhsiao.info 4365 N. Quad, 105 S. State St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. My current topic is focused on how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, sharing economy applications, can support newcomers in adapting to a new environment.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan

**Doctoral Candidate in Information** 

Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University M.S. in Computer Science

Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)

Visiting Scholar Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker

National Taiwan University

**B.S.** in Computer Science

Ann Arbor, MI, USA 09/2015 - present

Taipei, Taiwan

09/2010 - 06/2013

Moffett Field, CA, USA

07/2012 - 09/2012

Taipei, Taiwan 09/2006 - 06/2010

### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal Articles

• Hsiao, J. C.-Y. and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). Technology to Support Immigrant Access to Social Capital and Adaptation to a New Country. To appear in Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction. Vol. 2, CSCW, Article 70. (acceptance rate: 25.6%).

### Conference Proceeding Papers

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18), Article 37 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17), 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- Rajan, R., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13), 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).
- Tsai, W.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13), 5150-5160.

### Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17), 1700 - 1707 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015) Let's Solve It Together: Introducing Crowd Workers to Friendsourcing for Improving Creative Design. Presented at The Taiwan Computer-Human Interaction Workshop 2015 (Tai-CHI '15) (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15), 1893-1898 (Presenter).

### Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations (Cont.)

- Tsai, W.-C., Lee, H.-C., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Framing Design of Reminiscence Aids with Transactive Memory Theory. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2013 (CHI EA '13*), 331-336.
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao**, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). In Search of Lost Sounds: Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Everyday Soundscape. Presented at *The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems 2012 (DIS '12)*.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

### Unpublished Theses and Research Reports

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2018). Social Network Matters: Opportunities for Technologies to Support Immigrants' Jobseeking. Field Prelim, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2017). Can People-Nearby Applications Benefit Newly-Arrived Immigrants? An Exploratory Study. *Pre-candidacy research paper*, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2012). Assessing Engagement in Conversation by Hierarchically Decomposing Emotion and Interaction. *Master's Thesis*, Dept. of Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), Natl. Taiwan Univ.

### **HONOR**

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

2019

### Graduation Representative

Was chosen as the recognized master's student for leadership and active participation in student affairs of the department

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Research Assistant

09/2015 - present

Supported Dr. Dillahunt and research of the Social Innovations Group (SIG), which is focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and education (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

Workshop Organizer

03/2015 - 05/2015

Organized the collaborative workshop on design thinking of Stanford d.school and National Taiwan University IoX Center

Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Collaborative Researcher

07/2014 - 07/2015

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a SNS user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

Taiwan Army (Mandatory Military Service)

Taichung, Taiwan

Company Chief Consultant (Second Lieutenant)

08/2013 - 07/2014

Handled psychological consulting, human resources management, and welfare of a military company with 40+ members

Intelligent Agents Lab, Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

System Administrator

03/2011 - 07/2013

Managed devices and web services for 30+ lab members

ROFESSIONAL SERVICES	
Academic Events & Activities	
ACM MobileHCI 2019	09/2017 - Present
Student Volunteer Chair	04 /0045 05 /0045
TaiCHI 2015 Organizing Committee	01/2015 - 07/2015
OpenHCI Workshop 2014 (student-organized workshop on HCI in Taiwan) Steering Committee	01/2014 - 07/2014
OpenHCI Workshop 2013 Program Chair	01/2013 - 07/2013
OpenHCI Workshop 2011 Registration and Volunteer Chair	01/2011 - 07/2011
Social Events & Activities	
Univ. of Michigan, School of Information	08/2018 - Present
Doctoral Committee - Student Representative	
Annual Taiwan Night at CHI Organizing Committee	2015 - 2018

#### Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017 - 2019; ACM CSCW 2017, 2018; ACM MobileHCI 2018; ACM TEI 2017

### Conference Student Volunteer

ACM CSCW 2018; ACM COMPASS 2018; ACM CHI 2017

TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor	
School of Information, Univ. of Michigan	Winter 2018

SI-622: Usability Testing Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Fall 2017

SI-501: Contextual Inquiry
Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama
Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. &

Dept. Design, Natl. Taiwan Univ. of Tech. and Sci. Spring 2013

Advanced Human-Computer Interface/User-Oriented Innovation Design Instructor: Prof. Hsien-Hui Tang & Prof. Mike Y. Chen

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. Fall 2011

Introduction to Computer Science Instructor: Prof. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Student Team Coach

OpenHCI Workshop 2011 07/2011

## VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Autism Serves VolunteerTaipei, TaiwanStarRain Service Association for Autism02/2008 - 06/2013